Hello, everyone. Welcome back
to another great lesson here with
us at English Pod. My name is
Marco and I'm Erica and today
We're going to be in
one of my favorite sporting
events, which is F1
F1 racing. All right
So yeah, we're gonna be
talking about racing specifically
F1 which is a very popular
sport all over the world
Yeah, I think maybe
it's like number two and
popularity after
soccer. Yeah, I think so
I have no numbers to back that up
Well, they do travel everywhere.
They have races all over the
world and just people love it
So well, it is kind of a
cool thing it will going
300 kilometers per
hour in a car is pretty cool
All right, so let's not
delay this any longer.
Let's listen to our
dialogue for the first time
Welcome back racing fans
my name is Rickfield and
as always I'm joined by my
partner in crime Bob Copeland
We're in the last stretch of
this very exciting race and
Kimmy Rai Konin is leading
the pack with only four laps to go
They're heading to turn
three and Lewis Hamilton
tries to pass Rai Konin.
It's a close one and oh no
Hamilton hits the wall He came in too
fast jammed on the brakes and spun out
We have yellow flag and the pace
car is making its way to the track the
cleanup crew is towing the heavily
damaged car and the green flag drops
Rai Konin is still in
the lead with only two
laps to go smoke is
coming out of his car
He seems to be having engine
trouble. He makes his way
out of the pit and for none
though it also takes the lead
How unlucky for Rai Konin
and this race is over the
ladies in gentlemen Alonzo
takes the checkered flag
What an exciting race. I
always love a good crash when
it comes to car races I think
many people go to races
Expecting to see a crash. They
don't want to see people getting hurt.
No, but a little bit of
emotion of just car crashes
Yeah, a little little explosion here there.
All right
So now we saw some really
exciting language related to racing.
So why don't we look at that
now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway
All right, so we were
talking about that crash
and I think what led to
the crash was the driver
jammed on the brakes right he jammed
on the brakes to jam on the brakes
Okay, now if I jam on the
brakes you push the brakes
really really hard and really
quickly and really suddenly
Right, so you jam on the
brakes and you stop very quickly
So Lewis Hamilton jammed on the brakes
and consequently spun out to spin out
Okay in the present.
It would be spin out spin out
Okay, so imagine yourselves
driving your car on a
very wet road and then
you jam on the brakes, right?
So then the car you
kind of lose control of the
car and it starts to
spin it goes in circles
Uh-huh, that would be
to spin out. Mm-hmm.
This is actually happened to
me more than once really. Yeah
Were you okay? Yeah, I was fine.
I was fine. Okay, so the car spun out now
Enracing you always see
this really cool car come out
and be of head of everyone
when there's an accident
Right, that's called the pace
car the pace car pace car now
Why is it called the pace
car because it sets the pace?
Okay, the pace or the
speed so pace mean speed.
Uh-huh, so this car comes
out and no other car can pass it
Everyone must go at the same
speed right the pace car pace car
All right, so after there is
an accident the clean-up
crew must come out. Okay
clean-up crew clean-up crew
All right, so crew.
This is an interesting word
When we talk about a crew we talk
about a group of people who work together
Okay, but for example in
an office can I have a crew?
Not really not
commonly right yeah
It's people who work together and they use
their hands to work. They do manual labor
Okay, so I can save for
example a construction crew.
That's right or maybe the
ground crew at the airport
Okay, or the flight crew also at the
airport. All right. Well in the airplane
So that's a crew so clean-up
crew clean-up crew now
They came out to take
that car away that broke
in or damaged vehicle.
So they were towing it toe
Okay, the verb to toe to toe So what
does it mean when you toe something or
you toe a car you pull
something behind you?
So if you're a truck that might pull a car
behind you, that's a toe truck a toe truck
Mm-hmm now this happens
commonly if you park your
vehicle where you are
not supposed to that's right
And your car will get toe your
car gets towed. Yeah, very good
All right, so we saw five really
great words related to racing and now
Why don't we listen to
our dialogue again, and
then we'll look at some
other interesting phrases
Welcome back race fans my
name is Rick Fields and as always
I'm joined by my partner
in crime Bob Copeland
We're in the last stretch of
this very exciting race and
Kimi Rachonin is leading the
pack with only four laps to go
They are heading to turn 3D and
Lewis Hamilton tries to pass Rachonin
It's a close one and oh
no Hamilton hits the wall
He came in too fast
Jammed on the brakes and
spun out. We have a yellow
flag and the pace car is
making its way onto the track
The cleanup crew is towing the heavily
damaged car and the green flag drops
Rachonin is still in the
lead with only two laps to go
Smoke is coming out of his car.
He seems to be having engine trouble
He makes his way into the pit
and Fernando Alonso takes the lead
How unlucky for Rachonin
and this race is over
ladies and gentlemen.
Alonso takes the checkered flag
Okay, so now we're back
and I think it's time for
us to take a look at some
phrases in fluency builder
Fluency builder well even though
we're talking about F1 racing
a lot of the language can be
used in many different situations
So let's look at some of those phrases
now when Rick Fields introduced his co-host
He said my partner in crime
partner in crime partner in crime now
It's not that they're
actually committing a crime.
No. They're not
actually bank robbers
But it's a very common and
friendly way of saying my good
friend or my the person I do
everything with ride my co-worker
Yeah, but a co-worker
who's a really really good
friend who you spend
a lot of time with okay
So that's your partner in
crime. It's just a metaphor, right?
So partner in crime now.
What about the next phrase?
The last stretch the
last stretch last stretch
Okay, before we explain
this word. Let's listen to some
examples and then we'll
come back and talk about it
Example one
We have finally in the last stretch of a
very long week. I can't wait to go home
Example two
He's in the last stretch of his
college years and soon. He'll graduate
Okay, so I understand that
to mean like the final length
of time right the last or final
moments before an ending
Alright, so the last
stretch the last stretch
Now when you're on the last stretch
you just have a few minutes to go to go
Yeah, to go now this
preposition to and the verb
go is very easy, right?
Right, but if you say
Five minutes to go. What does
that mean? Five minutes left left.
Yeah, it doesn't mean it's five
minutes to actually leave, right?
Right. No, it means you you
must complete five minutes before
you can be finished. Okay,
so it's not about exiting right
I have five days to go
before I go on vacation
So it's not about you
actually going on the vacation.
It's about you
passing those five days
Can you give us another example?
How about we have 45 minutes
to go before the end of the day?
That's right, so to go
Left exactly to go. All right now.
Let's take a look at our last phrase
Close one a close one
a close one all right
another interesting phrase
made up of simple words
So let's listen to some
examples to help us understand it
Example one
That was a close one the
teacher almost caught me cheating
Example two
It's a close one.
We are tied and the game is almost over
Example three
My girlfriend almost found the presence.
I hit under the bed. It was a close one
Okay, so a close one. It means a
situation that is almost dangerous
But wasn't but wasn't
exactly that was a close one.
Mm-hmm. Okay,
so very good phrases
I think we can take a lot from this and
apply it outside of that one, right? Yeah
All right, so let's listen to
the dialogue for the last time
and then we'll come back
and talk about this great sport
You
Welcome back racing fans
my name is Rickfield, and
as always I'm joined by
my partnering crime Bob
Copeland We're in the last
stretch of this very exciting race and
kimmy Ryconan is leading the
pack with only four laps to go
They're heading to turn
three and Lewis Hamilton
tries to pass Ryconan. It's
their close one and oh no
Hamilton hits the wall. He came in too
fast jammed on the brakes and spun out.
We have yellow flag and the pace
car is making its way to the track
The cleanup crew is towing the heavily
damaged car and the green flag drops
Ryconan is still in the lead with only two
laps to go smoke is coming out of his car
He seems to be having engine
trouble. He makes his way
out of the pit and for not
knowing so takes the lead
How unlucky for Ryconan
and this race is over the
ladies and gentlemen Alonzo
takes the checkered flag
You
All right, so f1 racing Erica.
Do you like it? Do you watch it?
Yeah f1's pretty pretty neat.
Um, you know cars that drive fast
That's pretty interesting Well for
some people it isn't right like why do
I want to go to a race
and just see fast cars?
Okay, I would never
go to a race, but I think
it's I would maybe
watch the highlights on
Well actually this year it's
really exciting because again
We're gonna have a night race. I think
it's in Malaysia or somewhere in Asia
That they're gonna race at
night. Oh, so that's pretty special.
Huh? Well, it's like harder
to see and you're going really
All right, so I hear you're going
to the f1 this year. Yes this year
I'm gonna go to the Shanghai
circuit to watch the f1 race
So I'm really excited about that.
I haven't ever been to one
So it should be fun. All
right. Well, I hope you
get to see some interesting
things like car crashes
Peace cars. Yeah. Yeah. What about
you guys our listeners? Are you fans of f1?
Have you ever been to an f1 race exactly
send us your questions and comments and
Also your stories. I think we have
listeners from all over the world
We have a lot of listeners in Brazil,
and I know that there is a grand pre there
So tell us how did it how did it go? Do you
like it? You can visit us at EnglishPod.com
Where Marco and I are
around to answer your questions.
All right any Canadian
race car drivers?
Oh, uh, yeah, there was one
recently someone some something
All right, maybe their users
know which one is the Canadian
so we'll see you guys there.
Thanks for listening. Bye